So congratulations--you've now built a search engine.
所以恭喜你 你现在已经建成了一个搜索引擎了
You've got all of the components that you need for a search engine.
你有了建立搜索引擎所需的一切成分
You've got a way to collect a corpus,
比如收集语料库的方法
using a Web crawler that you built in the first 3 Units.
使用在前3个单元所做的网络爬虫
In Units 4 and 5, you figured out--
在单元4和5
and hopefully understood--how to build the index
你学过 也希望你领会了 如何建立索引
and then how to make it faster in Unit 5.
以及在单元5所学的如何让它运行的更快
And in Unit 6--what we've just finished--
在单元6 也就是刚刚完结的这个单元
you figured out how to rank the results.
你学过了如何为搜索结果排名
There's one little bit left:
还有一点
we haven't used those ranks,
我们尚未使用过这些排名
so one of the questions on your homework
所以你的作业的其中一个问题
will be using the ranks to get the best result.
将会是使用排名来获得最佳结果
If we want to get the best result, just having the dictionary ranks
如果我们想要得到最佳结果 只有字典排名
is not enough--we need to use that to find
是不够的 我们需要用它
the result that matches the query that has the best rank.
来找出排名最高 且符合查询要求的结果
And that's one of the questions that you'll do on the homework for this Unit.
这就是本单元的作业之一
There are a lot of other hard problems.
还有很多其他的比较困难的问题
So you have a few problems left to solve
所以在你能够建立一个搜索引擎 与谷歌竞争之前
before you can build a search engine that will compete with Google.
还有一些问题留待你来解决
Probably the hardest one: you've got to come up with a name.
可能最难的一个就是想出一个名字
This is really hard.
这真的很难
You could try "Yoogle",
你可以试试 Yoogle
You could try "DuckDuck Find".
或者 DuckDuck Find
None of those really work--you'll have to come up with a better name,
这些都不好 你必须想出一个更好的名字
and this is a pretty tough problem.
这是个很难的问题
Make sure to also talk to your Trademark lawyers.
确保和你的商标律师谈一谈
Another thing you'd like to be able to do
另外一件事是
is actually get your search engine on the Web
把你的搜索引擎放在网络上
so other people can send queries to it.
这样其他人可以发送查询要求
That's not something we're going to cover in this class,
这个问题不会在本课程中涉及
but if you take the Web Applications course
但如果你上了网络应用课程
that will start shortly after this class finishes,
在本课程结束之后 网络应用课程很快就会开始
you'll learn a lot about how to build
你会从中学到
Web applications and be able to do that.
如何建立网络应用
So congratulations--you've reached the end of Unit 6.
所以恭喜你 你到达了单元6的尾声
And this is actually the last technical content
实际上 这是本课程中
that will be in this course.
最后一部分技术性内容
Unit 7 will get you ready for the final exam and will give you
单元7将会让你为期末考试做好准备
some interesting examples of using Computing in Context.
并给你一些在具体情境中使用计算的有趣的例子
So congratulations. You've now finished building a search engine
所以恭喜你 你现在已经完成了建立搜索引擎的内容
and it actually does Page Ranking
事实上 它的网页排名
better than any search engine that existed before 1998.
比1998年之前的任何搜索引擎都要好
That's quite amazing.
这是很惊人的
I first want to also congratulate David for getting you to this point.
首先 我想要恭喜 David 是他将你们带到了这个程度
I think that's quite amazing and, honestly, he's put a lot of
我认为这非常了不起
sleepless nights into thisl.
老实说 他为此牺牲了很多睡眠时间
But also, i want to tell you: you guys are my heroes.
但我也想告诉你 你们是我的英雄
You got to a point where you reached something, I think,
我认为 你们在本课程中
really significant in this class--you actually learned how to--
真正学到了一些有意义的知识
And you programmed your own search engine.
你为自己的搜索引擎编写了程序
Now, I have to say--I'm a little bit jealous.
现在 我要说 我有些嫉妒了
When I was a student at college,
当我还是个大学生时
there was no search engines, and there wasn't even
根本没有搜索引擎
and ability for me to learn all this stuff.
我甚至根本没有能力去学习它
As for you, you've been afforded the ability to learn all this stuff.
对于你们来说 你们已经具备了学习这些知识的能力
But then you really got an amazing speed here.
然后 你们真的学得很快
That's something really, really significant.
这是非常了不起的
I hope--I mean, if you keep up that speed
我希望 如果你能保持这个速度
and keep improving yourself with that same speed and learn new things--
继续用这种速度提升自己 学习新知识
maybe in 3 or 4 years you are the next Google.
也许 3到4年以后 你就是下一个谷歌
That would be really amazing.
这真的很棒
Well, I think you're definitely on track to doing that,
我认为你现在正处在正确的轨道上
and I hope you'll take some of the courses that we'll start offering,
我希望你在以后能参加一些
as 200 available courses and more advanced courses later.
我们提供的200个课程 以及更高级的课程
This is the end of Unit 6--we're not going to have
单元6就到这里
any more technical content to the course.
我们不会再有任何技术性的内容了
Unit 7 is going to be all field trips and interviews,
单元7将全部都是实地考察和访谈
giving you some idea of how the things that you've learned in class
让你了解你在课程中学到的知识
fit into Context--and that should be a lot of fun.
如何在实际情景中应用 这应该会很有趣
The other thing that you'll have, as part of Unit 7,
单元7还有一部分
is the final exam.
是期末考试
And I hope everyone enjoys Homework 6
我希望每个人都喜欢第6次作业
and will be ready for the final next week. >>And I hope you enjoy the final exam.
并为下周的期末考试做好准备 我也希望你能喜欢期末考试